<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brent Hollers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brent Hollers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IaC Part 4: Lessons Learned: Cost, Challenges, and What&#39;s Next</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-4-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-4-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lessons-learned-cost-challenges-and-whats-next&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned: Cost, Challenges, and What&amp;rsquo;s Next&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 4 of 4: Building Production-Grade Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-vs-expectations&#34;&gt;Reality vs. Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;./part-1-from-manual-chaos-to-iac.md&#34;&gt;Parts 1-3&lt;/a&gt;, we built a production-grade absence tracking system with Terraform, monitoring, and CI/CD. The code worked. The architecture was sound. The deployment succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then we turned it on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This final article covers what actually happened in production: real costs, unexpected problems, decisions we&amp;rsquo;d change, and lessons that only come from running systems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IaC Part 3: Automating Everything: CI/CD, Monitoring, and Workflows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-3-automating-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-3-automating-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;automating-everything-cicd-monitoring-and-workflows&#34;&gt;Automating Everything: CI/CD, Monitoring, and Workflows&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 3 of 4: Building Production-Grade Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-infrastructure-to-operations&#34;&gt;From Infrastructure to Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;./part-1-from-manual-chaos-to-iac.md&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, we identified the business problem and designed our architecture. In &lt;a href=&#34;./part-2-building-with-terraform.md&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, we built secure, modular infrastructure with Terraform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But infrastructure alone isn&amp;rsquo;t production-ready.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A system is only as good as our ability to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Know when it breaks (monitoring)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy changes safely (CI/CD)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Automate business logic (workflows)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article covers making infrastructure operational:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IaC Part 2: Building Secure, Modular Infrastructure with Terraform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-2-building-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-2-building-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-secure-modular-infrastructure-with-terraform&#34;&gt;Building Secure, Modular Infrastructure with Terraform&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 2 of 4: Building Production-Grade Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-design-to-implementation&#34;&gt;From Design to Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;./part-1-from-manual-chaos-to-iac.md&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, we explored &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; we chose Infrastructure as Code and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; architecture we designed. We made critical decisions about cloud providers, networking, security, and workflow automation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now comes the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;: implementing these decisions in Terraform with production-ready patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the end of this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modular Terraform design philosophy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;VPC networking with public/private subnet isolation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Security group least-privilege implementation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HTTPS with Application Load Balancer and ACM&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common pitfalls and how to avoid them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target audience:&lt;/strong&gt; This is hands-on. We&amp;rsquo;re writing real Terraform code, explaining every decision, and showing patterns you can use immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IaC Part 1: From Manual Chaos to Infrastructure as Code: Designing a School Absence System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-1-building-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/absence-system-iac/part-1-building-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;from-manual-chaos-to-infrastructure-as-code-designing-a-school-absence-system&#34;&gt;From Manual Chaos to Infrastructure as Code: Designing a School Absence System&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 1 of 4: Building Production-Grade Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-745-am-problem&#34;&gt;The 7:45 AM Problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 7:45 AM on a Tuesday morning. The school secretary&amp;rsquo;s phone rings. It&amp;rsquo;s Mrs. Johnson calling in sick—again. The secretary scribbles a note on a sticky pad, crosses off Mrs. Johnson&amp;rsquo;s name on the coverage spreadsheet, and starts making calls to find a substitute for periods 3, 5, and 7.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Gotchas: ALBs vs NLBs and VPC Enpoints, What to know for the exam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fourth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:56:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fourth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-aws-architects-gotcha-list-two-concepts-that-trip-everyone-up&#34;&gt;The AWS Architect’s &amp;ldquo;Gotcha&amp;rdquo; List: Two Concepts That Trip Everyone Up&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I sat for the Solutions Architect exam, I breezed through the questions on EC2 and RDS. But there were two specific areas where I found myself staring at the screen, second-guessing my answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALB vs. NLB:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Both balance load, so why does it matter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VPC Endpoints:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Why are there two types, and why is one free?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the &amp;ldquo;silent killers&amp;rdquo; of the exam. They seem similar on the surface, but confusing them ensures a fail on scenario-based questions. Here is the simplest way to visualize them so you never mix them up again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Technical Program Manager and Cloud Architect with over 5 years of experience driving infrastructure modernization and enterprise-grade cloud transformations. My background is rooted in the practical application of cloud technologies; I hold an &lt;strong&gt;AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate&lt;/strong&gt; certification and a &lt;strong&gt;Postgraduate Certificate in Cloud Architecture&lt;/strong&gt; from the University of Texas at Austin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently serving as a Director of Information Technology, I specialize in navigating the complex lifecycle of cloud migration. I successfully led a full-scale network overhaul that included migrating on-premise servers and domain services to &lt;strong&gt;Azure Active Directory&lt;/strong&gt;, significantly improving security and scalability for hundreds of users. Beyond infrastructure, I design and deploy specialized cloud solutions, such as &lt;strong&gt;AWS containerized environments&lt;/strong&gt; for practical programming applications and cyber ranges for technical training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From On-Prem to Cloud-Native: A Federal Migration &amp; Modernization Journey </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To develop a more concrete understanding of modernization and migration strategies for complex systems which also has specific security, resiliency, and accessibility requirements, I chose to simulate a realistic Federal Cloud Transformation scenario—migrating a legacy, stateful mission application from an on-premise data center to AWS, and subsequently refactoring it into a secure, scalable, cloud-native architecture on Kubernetes.&#xA;The Scenario:&#xA;A federal agency is running a critical &amp;ldquo;Mission Status&amp;rdquo; application on aging on-premise hardware (Dell PowerEdge/VMware). The agency has a mandate to evacuate the data center (Cloud First Policy) and improve the application&amp;rsquo;s security posture and scalability (Modernization).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learned when preparing for the Cloud Solutions Architect Exam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:55:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leveling-up-my-journey-to-the-aws-solutions-architect-associate&#34;&gt;Leveling Up: My Journey to the AWS Solutions Architect Associate&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the AWS Cloud Practitioner exam is the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; of the cloud, the AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate (SAA-C03) is emphatically the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;why.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently passed the Solutions Architect exam, and I want to be transparent: this is a different beast entirely. It requires a significantly higher investment of prep time and mental energy. While the foundational exam tests your vocabulary, this exam tests your intuition and your ability to architect complex systems under specific constraints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Certification Prep: AWS Cloud Practitioner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-crush-the-aws-cloud-practitioner-exam-a-strategic-approach&#34;&gt;How to Crush the AWS Cloud Practitioner Exam: A Strategic Approach&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF-C02) is the starting line for many cloud journeys. Before diving into the technical weeds, it is important to understand what this exam actually is. It is a &lt;strong&gt;foundational&lt;/strong&gt; exam, meaning it is not designed to test your ability to debug complex code or configure intricate firewall rules. Instead, it tests your understanding of high-level principles, the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; of the AWS ecosystem, and the core concepts that drive cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why SQL Matters and How to Learn It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 04:55:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-tool-you-cant-avoid-why-sql-is-your-ticket-to-it-literacy&#34;&gt;The One Tool You Can’t Avoid: Why SQL is Your Ticket to IT Literacy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my previous articles, I covered the cloud giants (AWS) and how to architect systems within them. But there is a fundamental layer that sits underneath almost every sophisticated application, reporting dashboard, and business decision in the world: &lt;strong&gt;Data&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And the language of data is &lt;strong&gt;SQL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are entering the IT field—whether as a developer, a cloud architect, or a project manager—you cannot afford to be &amp;ldquo;data illiterate.&amp;rdquo; While Python and Java get the glory, SQL (Structured Query Language) pays the bills. It is the bridge between raw, messy information and the &amp;ldquo;Aha!&amp;rdquo; moments that drive business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
